<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-09T10:03:30+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:9090/Zen/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Zen - An online platform where urban culture meets the underground.</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Isaac Chukwumah captured by the lens of Nicole Loucaides</title><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/2019/11/05/Isaac-Chukwumah-captured-by-the-lens-of-Nicole-Loucaides/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Isaac Chukwumah captured by the lens of Nicole Loucaides" /><published>2019-11-05T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-11-05T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:9090/Zen/2019/11/05/Isaac-Chukwumah-captured-by-the-lens-of-Nicole-Loucaides</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:9090/Zen/2019/11/05/Isaac-Chukwumah-captured-by-the-lens-of-Nicole-Loucaides/">&lt;p&gt;Self-possessed and fierce, Mabel flips the music-world male gaze without missing a beat. With her truth-telling primed to take over, she talks pop parentage, poise and ‘potential lethal’ perfection.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Self-possessed and fierce, Mabel flips the music-world male gaze without missing a beat. With her truth-telling primed to take over, she talks pop parentage, poise and ‘potential lethal’ perfection.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:9090/Zen/assets/img/Cover-story.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Instagram Photographer Sexual Assault</title><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/03/Instagram-Photographer-Sexual-Assault/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Instagram Photographer Sexual Assault" /><published>2019-11-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-11-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/03/Instagram-Photographer-Sexual-Assault</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/03/Instagram-Photographer-Sexual-Assault/">&lt;p&gt;We report on some of it, but not all of it. We report on it if we think it reflects a bigger issue that hasn’t been completely understood by fashion or by consumers. Or if something has changed, like when the Mexican minister wrote a letter to Carolina Herrera. That’s meaningful because a national government is getting involved in one of these issues. Sometimes it can be gratuitous online or feel unfair. This is a big conversation that everyone is having and it is right to have it. The times have changed and so fashion’s approach to these issues needs to change. Things that were completely acceptable, that no one blinked at five years ago, are no longer acceptable. We have to both acknowledge that fashion has a history of appropriation and flash inspiration, and that it is deeply embedded in fashion and that has always been the case. It still needs to change. Those two things are not necessarily something we should get upset about, but that we need to acknowledge and try to grapple with.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="latest" /><summary type="html">We report on some of it, but not all of it. We report on it if we think it reflects a bigger issue that hasn’t been completely understood by fashion or by consumers. Or if something has changed, like when the Mexican minister wrote a letter to Carolina Herrera. That’s meaningful because a national government is getting involved in one of these issues. Sometimes it can be gratuitous online or feel unfair. This is a big conversation that everyone is having and it is right to have it. The times have changed and so fashion’s approach to these issues needs to change. Things that were completely acceptable, that no one blinked at five years ago, are no longer acceptable. We have to both acknowledge that fashion has a history of appropriation and flash inspiration, and that it is deeply embedded in fashion and that has always been the case. It still needs to change. Those two things are not necessarily something we should get upset about, but that we need to acknowledge and try to grapple with.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:9090/Zen/assets/img/ipsa.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">The Rise Of A New Age Model</title><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/03/Listen-to-Arca's-remix-of-Frank-Ocean-and-Skepta's-'Little-Demon'/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Rise Of A New Age Model" /><published>2019-11-03T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-11-03T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/03/Listen-to-Arca's-remix-of-Frank-Ocean-and-Skepta's-'Little%20Demon'</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/03/Listen-to-Arca's-remix-of-Frank-Ocean-and-Skepta's-'Little-Demon'/">&lt;p&gt;Self-possessed and fierce, Mabel flips the music-world male gaze without missing a beat. With her truth-telling primed to take over, she talks pop parentage, poise and ‘potential lethal’ perfection.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="latest" /><summary type="html">Self-possessed and fierce, Mabel flips the music-world male gaze without missing a beat. With her truth-telling primed to take over, she talks pop parentage, poise and ‘potential lethal’ perfection.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:9090/Zen/assets/img/troanam.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">6 Ways to Thrift for Contemporary Streetwear</title><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/A-6-Ways-to-Thrift-for-Contemporary-Streetwear/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="6 Ways to Thrift for Contemporary Streetwear" /><published>2019-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/A-6-Ways-to-Thrift-for-Contemporary-Streetwear</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/A-6-Ways-to-Thrift-for-Contemporary-Streetwear/">&lt;p&gt;From the proponents of in fashion streetwear to the reverberators of retro streetwear—a list that fills every cup of tea&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="latest" /><summary type="html">From the proponents of in fashion streetwear to the reverberators of retro streetwear—a list that fills every cup of tea</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:9090/Zen/assets/img/6wttfcs.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">A Manifesto of a Youth Activist</title><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/A-manifesto-of-a-Youth-Activist/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Manifesto of a Youth Activist" /><published>2019-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/A-manifesto-of-a-Youth-Activist</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/A-manifesto-of-a-Youth-Activist/">&lt;p&gt;This week, 19-year-old Norwegian editor and publisher Elise By Olsen (Recens Paper, Wallet) is the guest editor of AnOthermag.com, presenting a series of articles exploring the current and future state of fashion and art publishing. Alongside conversations with publishers, critics and image-makers, this guest edit offers an intimate insight into her own publications and working practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a collector of books, magazines and other publications for a long time. I vividly remember being around nine years old and dropping by the newsstand after school and purchasing some magazines with my pocket money, or else getting clavicle pain from lugging around backpacks full of them when travelling. This collection grew into my more developed personal bedroom library, which I am dedicated to building upon. I often think about Walter Benjamin’s essay Unpacking My Library: A Talk About Book Collecting and his intimate relationship with his library – and of course, I can relate. “To a book collector, you see, the true freedom of all books is somewhere on his shelves,” he writes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a publisher, I’m obviously immersed in fashion publishing and feel a responsibility to stay abreast of the field. Yet, when I was asked to recommend a reading list during a lecture at Central Saint Martins last year, I couldn’t think of a single publication. Instead, I remember saying how I think fashion criticism is in a poor state, unlike in other cultural spheres such as film and art, where criticism is a more embraced, or more respected, discipline. And obviously I could recommend a lot of fabulous visual fashion magazines, but publications for research… I sent the student home with a reading list totally unrelated to fashion. This got me thinking that I should really look into what I’m reading – so I went straight into my library and compiled a pile of my favourite fashion publications for research. Central Saint Martins students, this is for you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="latest" /><summary type="html">This week, 19-year-old Norwegian editor and publisher Elise By Olsen (Recens Paper, Wallet) is the guest editor of AnOthermag.com, presenting a series of articles exploring the current and future state of fashion and art publishing. Alongside conversations with publishers, critics and image-makers, this guest edit offers an intimate insight into her own publications and working practice. I’ve been a collector of books, magazines and other publications for a long time. I vividly remember being around nine years old and dropping by the newsstand after school and purchasing some magazines with my pocket money, or else getting clavicle pain from lugging around backpacks full of them when travelling. This collection grew into my more developed personal bedroom library, which I am dedicated to building upon. I often think about Walter Benjamin’s essay Unpacking My Library: A Talk About Book Collecting and his intimate relationship with his library – and of course, I can relate. “To a book collector, you see, the true freedom of all books is somewhere on his shelves,” he writes. As a publisher, I’m obviously immersed in fashion publishing and feel a responsibility to stay abreast of the field. Yet, when I was asked to recommend a reading list during a lecture at Central Saint Martins last year, I couldn’t think of a single publication. Instead, I remember saying how I think fashion criticism is in a poor state, unlike in other cultural spheres such as film and art, where criticism is a more embraced, or more respected, discipline. And obviously I could recommend a lot of fabulous visual fashion magazines, but publications for research… I sent the student home with a reading list totally unrelated to fashion. This got me thinking that I should really look into what I’m reading – so I went straight into my library and compiled a pile of my favourite fashion publications for research. Central Saint Martins students, this is for you.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:9090/assets/img/amoaya.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Guess Who Show up for the Zen Print Issue 01 Party</title><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/Guess-Who-Show-up-for-the-Zen-Print-Issue-01-Party/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Guess Who Show up for the Zen Print Issue 01 Party" /><published>2019-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/Guess-Who-Show-up-for-the-Zen-Print-Issue-01-Party</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/Guess-Who-Show-up-for-the-Zen-Print-Issue-01-Party/"></content><author><name></name></author><category term="latest" /><summary type="html"></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:9090/Zen/assets/img/gwsuftzpino.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">TSA and Adidas Collaboration</title><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/TSA-and-Adidas-Collaboration/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="TSA and Adidas Collaboration" /><published>2019-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-11-02T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/TSA-and-Adidas-Collaboration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/02/TSA-and-Adidas-Collaboration/">&lt;p&gt;We talk to TSA about his recent collaboration with adidas on the “Road Not Taken” campaign – “I always been a fun of adidas since I was a kid”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TSA is currently living in New York. “Whenever I am here, I feel like I belong than in any other place”. When growing up in London TSA always felt like an outsider. He started making music from a very young age, he enjoyed hanging with friends and watching movies. “We’re young men, and we didn’t know any better”. 
What were your first pair of shoes you bought? “That’s pretty obvious, Adidas! It is unbelievable, I never thought I would work with Adidas”. TSA is the main model for the autumn Adidas campaign focused on creating clothes with renewable fabrics. Most of us are familiar with Adidas first encounter  using renewable materials to reduce the production pollution with the Adidas Boost Foam. TSA gained recognition after producing John Mayer’s “3x5” the album was nominated twice and won a Grammy Award. Where were you when you found out you have been nominated? “I was at the studio working on my songs when John called and I was like ‘alright, alright’ a week later I was demystified then I called my mom”&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="latest" /><summary type="html">We talk to TSA about his recent collaboration with adidas on the “Road Not Taken” campaign – “I always been a fun of adidas since I was a kid”. TSA is currently living in New York. “Whenever I am here, I feel like I belong than in any other place”. When growing up in London TSA always felt like an outsider. He started making music from a very young age, he enjoyed hanging with friends and watching movies. “We’re young men, and we didn’t know any better”. What were your first pair of shoes you bought? “That’s pretty obvious, Adidas! It is unbelievable, I never thought I would work with Adidas”. TSA is the main model for the autumn Adidas campaign focused on creating clothes with renewable fabrics. Most of us are familiar with Adidas first encounter using renewable materials to reduce the production pollution with the Adidas Boost Foam. TSA gained recognition after producing John Mayer’s “3x5” the album was nominated twice and won a Grammy Award. Where were you when you found out you have been nominated? “I was at the studio working on my songs when John called and I was like ‘alright, alright’ a week later I was demystified then I called my mom”</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:9090/Zen/assets/img/taac.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We Are All Unconciously Inventing in the Cigaratte Economy</title><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/01/We-Are-All-Unconciously-Inventing-in-the-Cigaratte-Economy/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We Are All Unconciously Inventing in the Cigaratte Economy" /><published>2019-11-01T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-11-01T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/01/We-Are-All-Unconciously-Inventing-in-the-Cigaratte-Economy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/11/01/We-Are-All-Unconciously-Inventing-in-the-Cigaratte-Economy/">&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to be young these days? Generational theories help us better understand the last decades, but recent studies show the non-age-ranged youth demands for emancipation. Today, the speed human behaviour changes blurs the concept of generation, and makes it difficult to establish cuts in its timeline. 
Maybe being 60 is the new cool. I love to see will I look when I’m 48. If fashion is not about age the conversations around fashion between the older generations and some what younger people will be a lot shorter and intuitive. Maybe taking about what did last summer with 48 year is slowing becoming not a bad idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea of age is complex, and definitely subjective. One of the most iconic figures of contemporary culture is Pharrel, 40 years old. On the other hand, fashion editor Tavi Gevinson had an amazing comprehension of youth culture even before she was 18.
Youth is becoming less of an unquestionable inspiration, and excluding age range of the contemporary popular topics.
The Baby boomers, most populous of the generations, are today between their 48 and 66 years. And they will not stop getting older.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hollywood is obsessed with the idea that the 30s are the new 20s, the 40s are the new 30s,&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="latest" /><summary type="html">What does it mean to be young these days? Generational theories help us better understand the last decades, but recent studies show the non-age-ranged youth demands for emancipation. Today, the speed human behaviour changes blurs the concept of generation, and makes it difficult to establish cuts in its timeline. Maybe being 60 is the new cool. I love to see will I look when I’m 48. If fashion is not about age the conversations around fashion between the older generations and some what younger people will be a lot shorter and intuitive. Maybe taking about what did last summer with 48 year is slowing becoming not a bad idea. The idea of age is complex, and definitely subjective. One of the most iconic figures of contemporary culture is Pharrel, 40 years old. On the other hand, fashion editor Tavi Gevinson had an amazing comprehension of youth culture even before she was 18. Youth is becoming less of an unquestionable inspiration, and excluding age range of the contemporary popular topics. The Baby boomers, most populous of the generations, are today between their 48 and 66 years. And they will not stop getting older. Hollywood is obsessed with the idea that the 30s are the new 20s, the 40s are the new 30s,</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:9090/Zen/assets/img/waauiitce.jpeg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Basquiat-isms Ten of Jean-Michel’s Best Quotes</title><link href="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/10/31/Basquiat-isms-Ten-of-Jean-Michel-s-Best-Quotes/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Basquiat-isms Ten of Jean-Michel’s Best Quotes" /><published>2019-10-31T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2019-10-31T00:00:00+02:00</updated><id>http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/10/31/Basquiat--isms-Ten-of-Jean-Michel%E2%80%99s-Best-Quotes</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:9090/Zen/latest/2019/10/31/Basquiat-isms-Ten-of-Jean-Michel-s-Best-Quotes/">&lt;p&gt;As a child, photographer Cindy Sherman had an experience viewing a film which would leave an enduring impression on her, and go on to influence one of her greatest bodies of work. “I happened upon a movie told entirely through still images, except for one brief moment of motion”, she would later recall. “I didn’t remember the name of it, only the fact that I was entranced by the story told through these still images.” As an adult, she would re-encounter the film and discover it was Chris Marker’s La Jetée (1962), a story which he constructed almost exclusively through single static shots; a brief shot of a woman opening her eyes was the only moving image in the film. This interest in the ability to create narrative through single images would come to fruition in Sherman’s own work through her Untitled Film Stills (1977-1980). In this series of photographs, Sherman would create her own sequence of still images, but in contrast to Marker’s film, her shots were not intended to form a linear narrative. Instead, each image was designed to suggest the world of a different film in itself, inviting the viewer to imagine the story from which each image had been taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sherman plays all the characters in the Untitled Film Stills herself. But while the series has often been interpreted as a form of self-portraiture, she maintains the photographs are not autobiographical, and that they are entirely fictional and drawn from cinema. La Jetée would not be the only film to influence her work: the series also takes inspiration from a number of other notable films, directors, and actresses from the 1950s to the 1970s, while also challenging and reinventing the images of women seen in many of these films. In creating her series, Sherman drew from a wealth of film viewing experiences from many stages of her life, including early viewings of Hitchcock’s Rear Window, movie screenings attended while a student at Buffalo, and films she saw in New York after moving to the city in 1977.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="latest" /><summary type="html">As a child, photographer Cindy Sherman had an experience viewing a film which would leave an enduring impression on her, and go on to influence one of her greatest bodies of work. “I happened upon a movie told entirely through still images, except for one brief moment of motion”, she would later recall. “I didn’t remember the name of it, only the fact that I was entranced by the story told through these still images.” As an adult, she would re-encounter the film and discover it was Chris Marker’s La Jetée (1962), a story which he constructed almost exclusively through single static shots; a brief shot of a woman opening her eyes was the only moving image in the film. This interest in the ability to create narrative through single images would come to fruition in Sherman’s own work through her Untitled Film Stills (1977-1980). In this series of photographs, Sherman would create her own sequence of still images, but in contrast to Marker’s film, her shots were not intended to form a linear narrative. Instead, each image was designed to suggest the world of a different film in itself, inviting the viewer to imagine the story from which each image had been taken. Sherman plays all the characters in the Untitled Film Stills herself. But while the series has often been interpreted as a form of self-portraiture, she maintains the photographs are not autobiographical, and that they are entirely fictional and drawn from cinema. La Jetée would not be the only film to influence her work: the series also takes inspiration from a number of other notable films, directors, and actresses from the 1950s to the 1970s, while also challenging and reinventing the images of women seen in many of these films. In creating her series, Sherman drew from a wealth of film viewing experiences from many stages of her life, including early viewings of Hitchcock’s Rear Window, movie screenings attended while a student at Buffalo, and films she saw in New York after moving to the city in 1977.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:9090/Zen/assets/img/bitojmbq.jpeg" /></entry></feed>